Nicholas Osaka

■ nosaka@uncc.edu | 🖸 nosaka0 | 🛅 nosaka0

Summary_

I'm an undergraduate and early-entry master's Computer Science student at UNC Charlotte studying artificial intelligence. My research interests include computer vision, computational imaging, physical sensing via novel imagery techniques, and natural language processing. With my double major in Philosophy focusing on Ethics and Applied Philosophy, I'm prepared to approach complex issues in emerging technologies.

Education

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Charlotte, NC

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Graduation: May 2022

- Cumulative GPA: 4.0
- Concentration: Artificial Intelligence

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Charlotte, NC

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN PHILOSOPHY

Graduation: May 2022

· Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Skills

Programming Languages
Frameworks and libraries

Python, Java, Kotlin, C++, Java/TypeScript, Rust, HTML/CSS

es Tensorflow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, React, PyTest, JUnit

Software Tools and Skills Git, BASH, Linux, Docker, Agile/Scrum, Continuous Integration, Test Driven Development, LaTeX

Academic Work

Teaching Assistant for Intro to Natural Language Processing

Charlotte, NC

UNC CHARLOTTE DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2021 - Present

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Working to ensure high quality course experience for students through supplemental review sessions.}$
- Proactively analyzing student feedback throughout course to inform professor of issues before they arise.
- · Hold weekly office hours and tutoring sessions for students.

Teaching Assistant for Software Engineering

Charlotte, NC

UNC CHARLOTTE DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2020 - May 2021

- Acted as lead TA for a team of 3 other TAs.
- Worked collaboratively to create new lab elements to keep course materials updated.
- Proactively analyzed course statistics to provide information to drive course material decisions.
- Held weekly office hours and tutoring sessions for students.

Teaching Assistant for Intro to Computer Science I

Charlotte, NC

UNC CHARLOTTE DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

January 2019 - May 2020

- Led weekly lab instruction for over 30 students.
- Designed demonstrative code and interactive learning elements to facilitate active learning.
- Held weekly office hours and tutoring sessions for students.

Industry Experience

Technology & Data Intern — Leadership Development Program

Hartford, CT

THE HARTFORD

May 2021 - August 2021

- Interned remotely in the Leadership Development Program Ops, Tech, Data & Analytics track.
- Built a portfolio management intake tool for the Enterprise Data Office estimated to save over \$30k a year with three other interns.
- Led multiple meetings with different teams in order to identify best approach for architecture, deployment, and access control.
- Developed teamworking and leadership skills while working in a remote environment.
- Application included Node.js front and back ends, with an Express.js RESTful API layer which manages data exchange to database.
- · Analytics were integrated using Tableau for a Director to identify blockers and advance business initiatives.

Motion Graphic Designer

THE LITTLEFIELD COMPANY

Charlotte, NC

- · Designed motion graphic content for projects requiring displays of complex data.
- Translated clients quantitative needs into creative goals for projects.
- Interacted with clients to deliver final design under anticipated deadlines.
- Designed project asset organizational scheme for use in all company projects with motion graphics.

Videographer & Editor

Charlotte, NC

June 2017 - July 2017

April 2018 - May 2020

YOUNG ENGINEERS OF TODAY SUMMER CAMPS

- · Filmed and documented multiple camp activities for camps during the day, and edited simple videos for promotional purposes.
- · Gained understanding of asset management and project workflow. Used Adobe Premiere Pro for all projects.

Research and Projects_

NSF REU Research Project — Community Oversight for Privacy and Security

Charlotte, NC

UNC CHARLOTTE, CO-OPS PROJECT — DR. HEATHER LIPFORD

May 2020 - August 2020

- Designed and developed an Android mobile application with research intent.
- Implemented modern Android development practices with MVVM architecture and NoSQL databases.
- · Participated in weekly meetings to discuss research objectives and create solutions to challenging obstacles.
- Developed experience in Android, Kotlin, Firebase, and Room.

Undergraduate Research — Augmented Reality and Machine Learning for Medical Use

Charlotte, NC

UNC CHARLOTTE, AUTONOMOUS INTELLIGENT WIRELESS NETWORKED SYSTEMS LABORATORY — Dr. Pu Wang

December 2019 - May 2020

- Designed system for use in critical professions such as the medical industry.
- Utilized EPSON MOVERIO smart glasses in conjunction with Tensorflow Lite and other related technologies for user-inspired research in possible solutions for cognitive overload in error-critical professions.

Professional Affiliations

Secretary Charlotte, NC

AMNESTY INTERNATIONAL AT UNC CHARLOTTE

August 2021 - Present

- · Organizing internal documents and keeping detailed records of organization activities.
- Coordinating between other officers with respect to needs and solutions.
- · Create detailed meeting minutes for future reference.

Member

AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR ENGINEERING EDUCATION

November 2021 - Present

- Dues paying member of the American Society for Engineering Education Equity, Culture & Social Justice in Education Division.
- · Receives weekly organizational notices regarding conferences and papers.
- · Kept up to date on contemporary methods for STEM education that fosters equitable learning environments.

Certifications

2021	Engineering: Responsible Conduct of Research, Credential ID 41647235	CITI Program
2021	Social and Behavioral Sciences: Responsible Conduct of Research, Credential ID 41647234	CITI Program
2020	IRB Members: Basic Course, Credential ID 38222534	CITI Program

Honors

2018-2021	I Chancellor's List , UNC Charlotte — Awarded for earning above 3.8 GPA	Charlotte, NC
2020	Atkins Library Undergraduate Research Award, Office of Undergraduate Research	UNC Charlotte
2019	Student Marshal , UNC Charlotte — Selected based on academic performance	UNC Charlotte
2019	Phi Kappa Phi, Honor society	UNC Charlotte